# Josh Taguicana WWW.JOSHTAG.COM

## About

I am a new web developer dedicated to building creative, dynamic & future-proof websites while continuing to learn new skills in a work environment. I have previously worked in accounting, where I gained valuable organizational, time-management, and communication skills to solve problems individually and as part of a team.

# Skills

HTML 5 / CSS 3 / JavaScriptReact.JS / Node.JS / Express.JS / Vue.JS / MongoDB / Git / GitHub / GitLab

Also: Agile, SASS & BEM, MVC, Component-Based Architecture with React, NPM, RESTful API, Single-Page Applications, Model-View-Controller (MVC), Agile Software Development

# Projects

### **Warcraft Auctions**

A data visualization project aimed at giving World of Warcraft players information about the auction house to buy and sell and build their gold. Created for my BrainStation capstone.

## Star Wars Database

A simple database made to find Star Wars characters, spaceships, and planets. Made to teach myself react hooks and databases.

## Web Slayer

A turned based fighting game with a web developer theme. Created to teach myself Vue.js and Sketch.

## **Work Experience**

#### Web Development Teaching Assistant

BrainStation
June 2019-Present

- Managed and supported students in a classroom setting as well as motivated students to achieve personal goals throughout the course
- Facilitated discussions, solved problems, and addressed student grievances through pod sessions
- Assisted educators with the marking of student assignments, assessed prep course entrance assignments for prospective students
- Created daily challenges and white-boarding questions for students to assist with learning and understanding of the current weeks topic
- Improve learning experience through mentorship of student, implementing student feedback, and mini code alongs

### **Fund Accountant**

CIBC Mellon April 2018 - March 2019

- Ensured accuracy of a fund's trades, cash transactions, corporate actions, and verified
- Audited the work performed by other team members for the department to ensure accuracy and compliance with department and client instructions
- Calculated daily income accruals, expenses, interest, and dividend payments and ensured proper postings to the fund portfolio and analyzed daily changes in compliance with client exception tolerances
- Prepared daily and monthly distribution reports for clients as well as reinvestment calculations for distributions

correct pricing securities to properly calculate the value of the fund portfolio

#### **Quality Assurance Agent**

Money Key June 2019-Present

- Audited the highest amount of loans firm wide through ensuring compliance with business and state regulatory policies by analysis of pay frequency, pay averages, and leverage resulting in higher quality lending due diligence
- Lead in training programs to assist new employees familiarize themselves with company processes
- Process debits and credits batches to meet the daily deadline. Audit batches for accuracy and confirm with bank
- Generated and analyzed trend reports for sales leads and customer service calls for management and supervisor review, identifying a need for stricter verification policies and customer education

## Education

BrainStationFull-Time Web Development DiplomaJune 2019RyersonBachelor of Commerce - AccountingAugust 2016SheridonBusiness Administration - AccountingApril 2013

# **Contact Me**

joshtaguicana@gmail.com

(647) 929-6216

www.linkedin/in/joshua-taguicana

www.joshtag.com